Dorothy Norman Papers
Dorothy Norman Papers
1923-1967
Norman, Dorothy, 1905-1997.
55 linear ft.
Papers of the American author. Correspondence (1947-1967); manuscripts (1949-1965); research material (1937-1967); and published material (1923-1967). Bulk relates to book Nehru, the first sixty years, selected and edited by Norman.
149394
Biographical History
Dorothy Norman (1905-1997) was an American photographer, writer, editor, arts patron and advocate for social change. Born in Philadelphia, Norman is perhaps best known for her long and intimate relationship with photographer Alfred Stieglitz, whom she met in 1927 and who became her lover and mentor. Stieglitz encouraged Norman in her photography, and her work includes numerous photos of Steiglitz as well as portraits of Lewis Mumford, Theodore Dreiser, John Cage, Jawaharlal Nehru, and Indira Gandhi.
During the 1930s and 1940s the two became involved in various liberal causes, particularly civil rights, education, and independence for India and Israel. Norman was a founding member of New York City's Liberal Party, the American Emergency Food Committee for India, and The American Citizens' Committee for Economic Aid Abroad. She was a member of the Americans for Democratic Action and served on the boards of both the New York Urban League and the National Urban League.
In addition to her social activtism and photography work, Norman wrote a weekly column in The New York Post (1942-1949) and edited and published Twice a Year, (1938-1948), a journal of literature, the arts and civil liberties whose contributors included Richard Wright, Albert Camus, Jean-Paul Sartre and Bertolt Brecht. She wrote or edited numerous books including The Selected Writings of John Marin (1949), Nehru: The First Sixty Years (1965), a two-volume collection of the Indian leader's writings, Alfred Stieglitz: An American Seer (1970), the first full-length biography of the American modernist, Indira Gandhi: Letters to an American Friend (1985), and Encounters: a Memoir (1987).
[Portions of this biographical sketch adapted from "Dorothy Norman, 92, Writer Who Sought Social Change" by Roberta Smith, New York Times, April 14, 1997.]
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Dorothy Norman Papers consist of two separate accessions which have not been integrated. Both contain correspondence, manuscripts, research material, and published material. The bulk of the material relates to Norman's interest in India and to her book, Nehru: The First Sixty Years.
Original accession
Correspondence includes both incoming and outgoing correspondence.
Subject files includes published material, mimeographed material, maps, a tape and a blueprint.
Manuscripts contains drafts, galleys, and other iterations of articles and books. The vast majority of this material relates to Norman's book Nehru: The First Sixty Years.
Research material includes manuscripts, published material, and xeroxed material concerning India and material for the book Nehru: The First Sixth Years.
Published material contains articles, book reviews, brochures, catalogs, reports, magazines, newspapers, and newspaper clippings.
1968 Accession
The 1968 additions to the Dorothy Norman papers are divided into five groups: correspondence, manuscripts, India research material, Nehru research material, and published material.
Correspondence, 1953-1967, includes both incoming and outgoing letters, and relates primarily to Indian problems.
Manuscripts, 1949-1960, consists of correspondence about, bibliography for, and discarded pages from the manuscript of Mrs. Norman's book, Nehru: the first sixty years. Also included in this group is a report on India by Mrs. Norman, and a manuscript by S. S. Bhatnagar.
India research material, 1950-1967, includes both published and mimeographed material relevant to Mrs. Norman's interest in India. Nehru research material, 1928-1951, contains typescript notes and printed material used as background for Mrs. Norman's writings about Nehru.
Published material, 1923-1967, contains books, bulletins, news letters, newspapers, pamphlets, periodicals and reports about India.
Arrangement of the Collection
Original accession
Incoming correspondence is arranged alphabetically; outgoing correspondence is arranged chronologically. Subject files are arranged alphabetically by subject. Manuscripts are arranged alphabetically by type. Research material is arranged alphabetically by subject. Published material is arranged alphabetically by type; within that, material is arranged alphabetically by title with the exception of newspaper clippings and press releases, which are arranged chronologically by year.
1968 accession
Correspondence is arranged chronologically. Manuscripts are arranged alphabetically by type. India research material and Nehru research material is arranged alphabetically by subject. Published material is arranged alphabetically by title.
Subject and Genre Headings
Women Authors; Norman, Dorothy, 1905-1997 -- Archives.; Norman, Dorothy, 1905-1997. -- Nehru, the first sixty years.; Nehru, Jawaharlal, 1889-1964.; Women authors, American.; India -- Politics and government.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Galley proofs.; Manuscripts for publication.; Press releases.; Authors.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Dorothy Norman.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Incoming
    - A-I, 1947; 1949,; 1950,; 1952-1954,; 1958,; 1960-1963 (Box 1)
    - J-N, 1949; 1950,; 1952-1954,; 1960,; 1966 (Box 1)
    - P-V, Unidentified, 1949-1952; 1955,; 1960-1964 (Box 1)
  - Outgoing
    - 1949, 1951, 1958-1960, undated (Box 1)
- Subject files
  - Blueprints, undated (Box 2)
  - Citizens Committee for Expanded Aid Abroad, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Education, Health, Social Welfare, 1951; 1954,; 1955,; 1958 (Box 2)
  - Gandhi, 1940; 1948,; 1954,; undated (Box 2)
  - Indira Gandhi, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Kashmir
    - Articles, Newsletters, news clippings, press releases, 1951-1954; 1956,; 1957,; 1962,; undated (Box 3)
    - Pamphlets, 1948; 1950,; 1951 (Box 3)
  - Maps, 1950; undated (Box 3)
  - Pakistan
    - 1949, 1950 (Box 3)
    - 1951-1957, 1959, 1962, 1963, undated (Box 4)
  - Programs, 1944; 1947,; 1949,; 1950,; 1954,; 1961,; 1963-1965 (Box 4)
  - Radio Broadcasts, 1937; 1944,; 1952,; 1954,; 1957,; 1960-1963,; 1966 (Box 4)
  - Rainmaking, 1950 (Box 4)
  - Research Organizations, Various Governments, undated (Box 4)
  - United Nations, 1949; 1960,; undated (Box 4)
  - George D. Woods, 1963-1966 (Box 4)
- Manuscripts
  - Articles, 1951; undated (Box 5)
  - Book, Nehru: The First Sixty Years
    - Original Copy
      - Foreward, Introduction, Table of Contents, 1964 (Box 5)
      - Part I, Chapters 1-28, 3 folders (Box 5)
      - Part I, Chapters 29-32 (Box 6)
      - Part II, Chapters 1-19, 2 folders (Box 6)
      - Part III, Chapters 1-6 (Box 6)
      - Part III, Chapter 7 (Box 7)
      - Part IV, Chapters 1-9, 2 folders (Box 7)
      - Part V, Chapters 1-12, 2 folders (Box 7)
      - Part VI (Box 8)
      - Part VII (Box 8)
      - Part VIII (Box 8)
      - Part IX, Chapters 1-8 (Box 8)
      - Part IX, Chapters 9-16 (Box 9)
      - Part X, Chapters 1-13, 2 folders (Box 9)
      - Part XI (Box 9)
      - Part XII, Chapters 1-4 (Box 9)
      - Part XII, Chapters 5-10 (Box 10)
      - Appendix (Box 10)
    - Carbon Copy
      - Introduction and Dedication, 1983 (Box 10)
      - Table of Contents (Box 10)
      - Part I, pp. 1-129, 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Part I, pp. 130-354, 3 folders (Box 11)
      - Part II, pp. 1-139, 2 folders (Box 11)
      - Part II, pp. 140-193 (Box 12)
      - Part III, pp. 0-167, 3 folders (Box 12)
      - Part IV, pp. 1-111, 2 folders (Box 12)
      - Part IV, pp. 112-160 (Box 13)
      - Part V, pp. 1-158, 3 folders (Box 13)
      - Part VI, pp. 1-97, 2 folders (Box 13)
      - Part VII, pp. 0-115, 2 folders (Box 14)
      - Part VIII, pp. 0-91, 2 folders (Box 14)
      - Part IX, pp. 1-60 (Box 14)
      - Part IX, 61-184, 2 folders (Box 15)
      - Part X, pp. 1-131, 3 folders (Box 15)
      - Part XI (Box 16)
      - Part XII, pp. 1-101, 2 folders (Box 16)
      - Appendix (corrected) (Box 16)
      - Index
        - Corrected for Proof (Box 16)
        - With corrections (Box 16)
    - Galley Proofs
      - Appendix, Contents, Bibliography, Glossary (Box 17)
      - Parts I-X, 10 folders (Box 17)
      - Parts XI-XII, 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Marked Galley Proofs, 1964
      - Parts I-III, 3 folders (Box 18)
      - Parts IV-XI, 8 folders (Box 19)
      - Part XII, Appendix, 1965 (Box 20)
    - Page Proof, 1964 (Box 20)
    - Sample Pages, 1963 (Box 20)
    - Uncorrected Proof Copy, 1964 (Box 20)
    - Discarded Pages
      - Part I (Box 20)
      - Parts II-XVI, 8 folders (Box 21)
      - Appendix (Box 22)
      - Part and Page not identified (Box 22)
  - Notes, undated (Box 22)
  - Manuscripts of others on India, 1949; 1950,; undated (Box 22)
  - Not Identified, undated (Box 22)
- Research material
  - India
    - Addresses, 1947-1954; 1965 (Box 23)
    - Aid, 1953; 1954 (Box 23)
    - Culture, 1943; 1947,; 1950-1955,; 1958,; 1961,; undated; 2 folders (Box 23)
    - General
      - 1940-1950, 1952-1954, 4 folders (Box 24)
      - 1955-1961, 1966 (Box 25)
      - Undated (Box 25)
      - Newspaper Clippings, 1952-1953 (Box 25)
    - Internal Affairs, 1947; 1948,; 1950,; 1953,; 1954,; undated (Box 25)
    - International Affairs, 1949-1957; 1961-1962,; 1966,; undated; 4 folders (Box 26)
    - Language Question, 1965 (Box 26)
    - Reports, 1949; undated (Box 26)
    - Statements, 1954 (Box 27)
    - and the United States, 1949; 1951-1955,; 1966,; undated (Box 27)
  - Nehru
    - General, 1937; 1944,; 1949-1951,; 1955,; 1959,; 1962,; 1964,; 1966 (Box 27)
    - Indiagrams
      - 1952-1956, 2 folders (Box 27)
      - 1957-1959 (Box 28)
    - Pages from Biography by J.S. Bright, 1946 (Box 28)
    - Pamphlet Clippings (Xeroxed), 1940-1949 (Box 28)
    - Quotes from books by (Box 28)
    - Statements, newspaper clippings, 1950-1951 (Box 28)
  - Nehru Book
    - Bibliography and Glossary, undated (Box 29)
    - Discarded Material, 1937; 1939,; 1950-1959,; undated; 4 folders (Box 29)
    - Excerpts from Campbell-Johnson book (Box 29)
- Published material
  - Articles by and about others, 1946; 1966,; undated (Box 30)
  - Book Review by, 1950 (Box 30)
  - Book by Others, 1948 (Box 30)
  - Brochures, 1948; 1949,; 1953,; 1955,; 1956,; 1961,; 1966 (Box 30)
  - Catalogues, 1948-1950; 1952,; 1956,; 1959,; 1965,; 1966 (Box 30)
  - Report by, 1960 (Box 30)
  - Bulletins A-U, 1943-1945; 1947-1955,; 1958-1967 (Box 31)
  - Magazines
    - A, 1939; 1940,; 1942-1945,; 1950,; 1955,; 1963,; 1965,; 1966 (Box 31)
    - Eastern Economist, 1949; 1952,; 1953,; 1957,; 1959,; 1960,; 1964 (Box 32)
    - E-L, 1946-1957; 1959,; 1961-1964,; 1966 (Box 33)
    - The March of India, 1949; 1951-1957 (Box 34)
    - The March of India, 1958-1962 (Box 35)
    - M-P, 1942; 1949-1954,; 1960,; 1962,; 1966 (Box 35)
    - R-T, 1948-1954; 1959,; 1961-1967 (Box 36)
    - U, 1950; 1951,; 1954,; 1956-1964 (Box 37)
    - UNESCO Courier-W, 1944; 1948,; 1950,; 1952-1965 (Box 38)
  - Newsletters, 1948; 1950,; 1952-1959,; 1961,; 1964,; 1966 (Box 38)
  - Newspaper Clippings
    - 1947-1950 (Box 38)
    - 1950-1959 (Box 39)
    - 1960 (Box 40)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 41)
    - 1961 (Box 42)
    - 1961-1963 (Box 43)
    - 1964-1966, undated (Box 44)
  - Newspapers
    - The Asian Student, 1963-1964 (Box 45)
    - The Hindu Weekly Review, 1954-1966 (Box 45)
    - India News, 1950; 1956,; 1957,; 1966 (Box 46)
    - Indian and Foreign Review, 1963-1966 (Box 46)
    - Kurukshetra, 1949; 1950 (Box 46)
    - The Overseas Hindustan Times, 1953-1956 (Box 46)
    - Shankar's Weekly, 1949 (Box 46)
  - Pamphlets
    - A-W, 1937-1939; 1942-1963 (Box 47)
  - Press Releases
    - 1947-1959 (Box 48)
    - 1960-1963 (Box 49)
    - 1964-1966, undated (Box 50)
  - Reports
    - A-R, 1942; 1943,; 1946,; 1949-1953,; 1955-1957,; 1962,; 1964-1966 (Box 50)
    - S-W, 1949-1252; 1954,; 1959,; 1960,; 1962,; 1963 (Box 51)
- Correspondence (1968 Accession)
  - 1958-1967 (Box 52)
- Manuscripts (1968 Accession)
  - Books
    - Nehru: the first sixty years
      - Correspondence concerning bibliography, 1953-1964 (Box 52)
      - Bibliography cards (Box 52)
      - Bibliography lists concerning Nehru (Box 52)
      - Bibliography, books by Nehru (Box 52)
      - Discards, original typescript
        - Glossary (Box 52)
        - Glossary (Box 53)
        - Part I-IX (Box 53)
        - Part X-XII, unidentified (Box 54)
  - Reports
    - "India fact sheet", 1960 (Box 54)
    - S. S. Bhatnagar, "Science and government", 1949; typescript carbon (Box 54)
- India Research Material (1968 Accession)
  - Asia, 1950-1962 (Box 54)
  - Asia Society, 1963 (Box 54)
  - Asia Society, 1964-1966 (Box 55)
  - Book catalogues, 1952-1959 (Box 55)
  - The Colombo Plan, 1950 (Box 55)
  - Desai, Moraji, Deputy Prime Minister of India (Box 55)
  - Indo-American relations (Box 55)
  - Information Service of India
    - Indiagrams, 1960-1967 (Box 55)
    - Special press releases, 1967 (Box 55)
  - News clippings, 1954-1967 (Box 55)
  - Portugal, 1961 (Box 55)
  - Publications in Sanskrit (?) (Box 55)
  - Ramakrishna Mission Institute of Culture, 1950 (Box 55)
  - Trade, 1958 (Box 55)
  - United States policy and program in Southeast Asia, 1953-1959 (Box 55)
- Nehru research material (1968 Accession)
  - Africa, 1951 (Box 55)
  - Chronology (Nehru), original typescript (Box 55)
  - Clippings from books by Nehru
    - The Cripps mission (Box 56)
    - The discovery of India (Box 56)
    - Independence and after (Box 56)
    - Soviet Russia (Box 56)
    - Visit to America (Box 56)
  - Letters (Nehru), printed material and 1 photograph of letter from Nehru to Mr. Oza, 1968 (Box 56)
  - Miscellaneous clippings from books (Box 56)
  - News clippings, 1950-1951 (Box 56)
  - Notes, quotes from books, typescript (Box 56)
  - Pakistan, 1950 (Box 56)
  - Press conferences (Nehru), 1950 (Box 56)
  - Speeches (Nehru), 1949-1957 (Box 56)
- Published material (1968 Accession)
  - Books
    - Anantanarayanan, M., The silver pilgrimage, N.Y. Criterion Books, 1961 (Box 57)
    - Dwarkadas, Kanji, Housing Indian labour, Bombay, Thacker and Co. Ltd., 1945 (Box 57)
    - Dwarkadas, Kanji, Bombay's slums: Matunga labour camp, Bombay, the author, 1949 (Box 57)
    - Gandhi, M.K., Letters to Rajkumari Amrit Kaur, Ahmedabad, Navajivan Publishing House, 1961 (Box 57)
    - Kripalani, J.B., The latest fad, Madras, Central Art Press, 1948 (Box 57)
    - Lord, Bette Bao, Eighth moon, N.Y., Harper and Row, 1964 (Box 57)
    - McGovern, William, To Lhasa in disguise, N.Y. Century Company, 1924 (Box 57)
    - R.K.P., Elements of village administration and law, Sevagram Wardha, India, Krishnadas Gandhi, 1948 (Box 57)
    - Sahni, J.N., Across twentieth parallel, New Delhi, Sahni, 1952 (Box 57)
    - Sovani, N.V., Post-war inflation in India, Poona, Gokhale Institute of Politics and Economics, 1949 (Box 57)
    - Sovani, N.V., Planning of post-war economic development in India, Poona, Gokhale Institute of Politics and Economics, 1951 (Box 57)
    - Stanton, Edwin F., Brief authority, New York, Harper's, 1956 (Box 57)
  - Bulletins
    - The Asia Foundation, 1957-1963; 17 items (Box 57)
    - Background, 1963; 1 item (Box 57)
    - Bulletin from the European Community, 1958; 1 item (Box 57)
    - Congress Bulletin, All India Congress Committee, 1945-1946; 2 items (Box 57)
    - Foreign Policy Bulletin, 1959-1960; 2 items (Box 57)
    - Freedom First, 1958-1967; 8 items (Box 57)
    - India Briefing, 1965-1967; 6 items (Box 57)
    - India Trade Bulletin, 1959; 1 item (Box 57)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art Bulletin, 1966; 1 item (Box 57)
    - Tata Institute of Social Sciences Bulletin, 1950-1951; 1 item (Box 57)
    - Trade Talk, 1957-1959; 2 items (Box 57)
  - Newsletters
    - The Asia Society Calendar, 1963-1967; 12 items (Box 57)
    - Asia Society Letter, 1958-1960; 11 items (Box 57)
    - Newsletter of the Committee on South Asia, 1958-1961; 5 items (Box 57)
    - Through the Bamboo Curtain, 1963; 1 item (Box 57)
  - Newspapers
    - The Indian Express, 1966-1967; 22 items (Box 57)
    - The Hindustan Times, 109 items (Box 58)
  - Pamphlets
    - Address by B.G. Kher, 1949 (Box 59)
    - Address by M. Asaf Ali, 1 Mar 1950 (Box 59)
    - "Agenda 1961: New Principles for a New Age" (Box 59)
    - "The All-India Women's Conference", undated; different topics; 3 copies (Box 59)
    - "The Asia Foundation," June, 1959 (Box 59)
    - Asian African Conference, 18-24 April 1955; Nehru's speeches (Box 59)
    - "Aspects of Education," B.G. Kher, 1948 (Box 59)
    - "Better Acquainted," Air India, undated (Box 59)
    - Bharat Sewak Samaj, 12 Aug 1952; 3 copies (Box 59)
    - "Bird's eye view of 36 years of Co-operation in Hyderabad State", 1945-1949 (Box 59)
    - "Bombay Marches On", 1950 (Box 59)
    - "Bombay Marches On — Education", 1951 (Box 59)
    - "Broadcast Talks," K.N. Katju, 14-18 Aug 1949 (Box 59)
    - "Building a Mutual Defense", April 1, 1951-October 9, 1951 (Box 59)
    - "Building a Sound Economy", November 1951 (Box 59)
    - "Building for Tomorrow", January 1954 (Box 59)
    - "Call to the Plow", 1947-1948 (Box 59)
    - "Consumer Co-operative in India During War-Time", 1944; 1945,; 1946 (Box 59)
    - "Consumer's Co-operative Commonwealth," G.S. Bhartiya, May, 1949 (Box 59)
    - "Co-operation and the Community", 1946 (Box 59)
    - "Co-operation in Assam (a new experiment)", 1945-1946 (Box 59)
    - "Co-operative Planning in Bombay Provinces," September, 1947 (Box 59)
    - "Creed vs. Policy of Non-Violence," K.N. Katju, 1949 (Box 59)
    - "Dateline... Saigon", undated (Box 59)
    - "Defense Services Science Exhibition", January 21-24, 1950 (Box 59)
    - "Defending Our Frontiers", December, 1951 (Box 59)
    - "Democracy on the March", September, 1951 (Box 59)
    - "United States Department of Commerce in Foreign Technical Assistance", 1952 (Box 59)
    - "The Development Decade in the Balance," G.D. Woods, January 1966 (Box 59)
    - "Development of Essential Oil Industry in V.P.", undated (Box 59)
    - "Development of Handmade Paper Industry", undated (Box 59)
    - "Department of Scientific Research & Council of Scientific & Industrial Research", April 1949; undated; 2 copies (Box 59)
    - "An Economic and Social Service," D.P. Mukerji, October 1948 (Box 59)
    - "Education for Democracy,", January 1952 (Box 59)
    - "Educational Exchanges,", December 1949 (Box 59)
    - "Facts about Foreign Trade,", April 1958 (Box 59)
    - "Flowers in the Desert," (Education), undated (Box 59)
    - "For Better Health,", December 1951 (Box 59)
    - "Foreign Trade: Challenge to Americans," James L. Vizzaro, April 1958 (Box 59)
    - "Four Years of the United Nations," B.P. Lamb, August-September 1949 (Box 59)
    - "Ghee Co-operatives in Uttat Pradesh,", 1950 (Box 59)
    - "Glimpses of Co-operation in Bombay,", 1950 (Box 59)
    - "The Golden Fibre,", August 1948 (Box 59)
    - "A Guide to Maganradi", 1947 (Box 59)
    - "Guidance to Students Desiring Information on Advanced Study in the United States of America,", March 1952; 2 copies (Box 59)
    - "The Harijan Movement," S.R. Nehru, 1940 (Box 59)
    - "Health Co-operatives,", 1949? (Box 59)
    - "Helping You to Grow More Food", 1949 (Box 59)
    - "Homage,", January 29, 1948 (Box 59)
    - "Home Guards", undated (Box 59)
    - "The Hyderabad Agricultural Co-operative Association Limited", undated (Box 59)
    - "The Hyderabad Agricultural Co-operative Union, Limited", undated (Box 59)
    - "The Hyderabad Problem", 1948 (Box 59)
    - "Hyderabad Reborn,", September 18, 1948-March 17, 1949 (Box 59)
    - "Hydro-Electric Development in India,", 1948 (Box 59)
    - "India,", June, 1948 (Box 59)
    - "India Goes to the Polls", 1967 (Box 59)
    - "The Interrupted Dialogue," B.K. Nehru, November 1, 1966 (Box 59)
    - "Introduction to India," B.P. Lamb, October, 1960 (Box 59)
    - "I Shall Serve All Equally", 1947 (Box 59)
    - "Kalakshetra,", November 17, 1959 (Box 59)
    - "Labour Legislation in India," ArS. Deshpande, undated (Box 59)
    - "Labor College," 8 pamphlets, January 6, 1947-November 30, 1947 (Box 59)
    - "Labour Governments at Work", 1949 (Box 59)
    - "Messages", 1961 (Box 59)
    - "Millions on the Move", undated (Box 59)
    - "More from Mother Earth,", July, 1951 (Box 59)
    - "More Typical Non-Credit Societies in India,", undated (Box 59)
    - "Mother and Baby Week,", February 7-14, 1949 (Box 59)
    - "Muscle Can Do It", undated (Box 59)
    - "My Work as Labour Officer," K. Dwarkadas, February 17, 1950 (Box 59)
    - "The National Chemical Laboratory of India, Poona", undated (Box 59)
    - "Nationalism of Coal in India,", August, 1948 (Box 59)
    - "New Burma Road", 1956 (Box 59)
    - "A New Mughel Mint", 1949 (Box 59)
    - "New Projects for Irrigation and Power in India", 1950 (Box 59)
    - "On the Home Front,", October, 1951 (Box 59)
    - "Organization to Economic Cooperation and Development,", December 14, 1960 (Box 59)
    - "Our Roads", 1949 (Box 59)
    - "Our Struggle for Freedom," Dr. Najib-Ullab, November, 1951 (Box 59)
    - "The Outlook for the United Nations," M.R. Masani, June 26, 1947 (Box 59)
    - "Pakhtoonistan and World Peace," Dr. Najib-Ullah, January 11, 1951 (Box 59)
    - "The Pakhtun Question", undated (Box 59)
    - "Pakistan Persecutes Christians,", February, 1964 (Box 59)
    - "Pandit Jawaharlal at the Bar," Dr. K.N. Katju, undated (Box 59)
    - "Passive Resistance in S. Africa," K.N. Menon, 1952; 2 copies (Box 59)
    - "Piper and the Tune," A. Mehta, 1949 (Box 59)
    - "Point Four and Liberia", 1953 (Box 59)
    - "Point Four, What it is, How it works,", 1953 (Box 59)
    - "Point Four Profiles", 1953 (Box 59)
    - "Prepare Your Own Manures This Easy Way,", undated (Box 59)
    - "Privileges Provided by the Bombay Government for the Backward Classes,", September 30, 1949 (Box 59)
    - "Progress of Science,", December, 1951 (Box 59)
    - "Prohibition Law in Bombay Province,", December 1, 1949 (Box 59)
    - "Projects for Plenty,", July, 1951 (Box 59)
    - "Protect Food and Seed Grains from Insects, Rats, and Moulds,", November 3, 1949 (Box 59)
    - "Protecting Your Crops", 1950 (Box 59)
    - "The Railways Go Ahead,", October, 1951 (Box 59)
    - "Reclamation of Kansland,", undated; 2 copies (Box 59)
    - "Rehabilitating the Uprooted,", January, 1951 (Box 59)
    - "Rehabilitation of Displaced Persons,", August, 1947 (Box 59)
    - "The Role of Voluntary Agencies in Technical Assistance, May, 1953 (Box 59)
    - "Self Inquiry", 1952 (Box 59)
    - "Self-Sufficiency in Food", undated (Box 59)
    - "The Seventh Tuberculosis Worker's Conference,", November 23, 1949; 2 copies (Box 59)
    - "Sherlock Holmes in Action in Real Life," K.N. Katju, undated (Box 59)
    - "Sherlock Holmes in India," K.N. Katju, undated; 2 different stories (Box 59)
    - "South Africa on the Nazi Path,", October, 1952 (Box 59)
    - Speech by Liaquat Ali Khan, February 20, 1949 (Box 59)
    - Speeches by Sir Mohummad Zafrullah Khan, January 24 and February 3, 4, 6, 11, 18, 1948 (Box 59)
    - "Square Deal for Labour,", September 1951 (Box 59)
    - State Hotel, Aurangabad, India, undated (Box 59)
    - "The Story of My Father," K.N. Katju, undated (Box 59)
    - "The Tashkent Declaration,", January 10, 1967 (Box 59)
    - "Technical Assistance,", February, March, April 1957 (Box 59)
    - "Textile Labour Association", 1948 (Box 59)
    - "The Three Pillars of State, 1949 (Box 59)